August
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
Saionji-sensei...
Please get a little sleep.
I'm fine...
In fact, if I fall asleep
now, I won't get this done.
Hey.
Let's get a breath of fresh air.
We're taking a break.
Okay.
See you later.
You guys take a break too
when you get a chance.
Call my cell if you need anything.
We'll squeak by tonight.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's hot...
It's like ice.
You're too cold.
Well, if I turn off the AC, the boys
mess up the manuscript with their sweat.
The body can cool down
from stress, too...
Oh yeah?
About that new offer you were
talking about the other day...
I don't think letting the quality
of your current work drop
is worth taking it on...
But Ma-chan, you don't really have
a strong constitution or will.
And you're making a
decent living as it is,
so there's no need to be greedy.
But...
What?
Right now, the spotlight's on me,
but who knows what'll happen next year.
There'll be younger artists
coming out of the woodwork.
They could turn their back
on me, just like that.
Ma-chan, you worry too much
about what could go wrong.
It's unhealthy.
You have an ink mark on your face again.
Oh yeah?
Tch...
Ma-chan, you're a girl, so...
I'm not a girl!
I'm a manga artist!
I'm going home to work!
I'm sorry for making a scene...
Jeez...
Pain in the ass to go to work...
Good morning...
Morning...
I called you before.
Sorry. It was just so hot...
Are you cooling off by doing that?
Yeah.
Wanna make your lunch?
Yeah!
Hey, you!
Give me a hand here!
Okay!
Rin's summer vacation has started.
In the morning, we make
her lunch together,
and then Rin goes to a day-care center.
How about we visit Grandpa's
grave next Saturday?
It's almost O-Bon,
[ Note: O-Bon = Holiday in which
people honor their ancestors ]
and since it's your...
What? You don't wanna go?
After all, the bellflowers
haven't bloomed yet...
It looks like it'll take
a little more time.
Well, this time, we'll
buy flowers at a florist,
and we can go again when
your flowers bloom.
I guess...
You'd make Grandpa happy bringing
him the bellflowers that you grew.
See? That's what I thought!
But what would make Grandpa
happiest is for you to visit.
That's number one.
Yeah...
Okay.
If Rin weren't here, I probably
wouldn't be thinking of Grandpa like this.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun!
If you move, it screws
the whole thing up!
Whoopsie!
Why is your hair so fine to begin with?
Apricot
I dunno!
What?
Wait a second!
Hey! We're gonna be late!
What's with him?
Daikichi, how many more days?
O-Bon Festival
About ten, I guess...
I found one!
A cicada shell!
A shell?
Huh. This brings back memories...
I've got a bunch of 'em in here.
Gross!
Don't shake 'em!
We're gonna be late!
Hey!
Watch out for cars!
I've been here a lot of times before.
With Grandpa?
Yeah.
I see. Grandma's laid to rest
here too, come to think of it.
Grandpa's grandma?
No, my grandma.
Um, Grandpa and Grandma's
child is my mom.
And I'm her son.
Your mother is Grandpa's daughter!
But...
Then that makes me your
mother's sister...
Crap! I don't want her to
go in this direction...
Over here!
Here it is!
Kaga Family Grave
The grave's wet.
That jar...
Masako-san had it...
Ma...
What the hell? When she didn't
even come to his funeral!
Rin, I'll be right back!
Stay here for a bit!
Pull up the weeds for me!
Okay!
What should I do?
I mean, she goes with a
man to visit the grave?!
Bark! Bark!
What?! What are you doing here?
I thought you were some
deranged person...
I'm supposed to be visiting a grave.
Accent on the "supposed to be"...
But I thought maybe I
should let you know...
Rin's here, too.
At Grandpa's grave...
Um, I...
Um, look, Rin's dear to me, so to be
honest, I don't often think about you.
I don't give a damn about
your circumstances either.
Unless Rin wishes for it, I have no
intention of ever getting you two together.
I know that.
But you went out of your way
to follow me, to say what?
Do you want to at least get
a look at Rin secretly?
Now, we're going to clean the grave off,
light incense and go home like normal.
I think it'll take some time...
Well, Rin is waiting for me.
So do what you want.
We're just gonna go about our business.
Rin... Sorry...
Was I gone long?
Um...
Are you okay?
Um... I had to do something...
Never mind, sorry.
Did you wait long?
Not too long.
Were you lonely?
You're weird!
Why are you so nervous?
I'm not weird.
Here.
Right.
Hold it out there.
Okay.
She's no longer a baby...
Blood ties are an amazing thing.
Yep. She looks just like you, Ma-chan.
From behind...
She's pretty cute.
From this sense of distance...
He closely resembles Souichi-san...
Good...
That was a surprise.
Maybe a coincidence like this happens
because it's nearly O-Bon...
She's seven years old today...
I see...
I was surprised about
your daughter, of course,
but I thought maybe he
was your ex-boyfriend...
Give me a break.
I don't think that man's
got a lick of intelligence.
Although I can't say what he'd be
like given another half a century...
Half... a century?
I suppose that man was her boyfriend...
Hey, Daikichi?
And far be it for me to say it's bad...
Daikichi!
But some people...
Well, she sure found herself
a sweetheart fast enough...
Daikichi, I said!
Yes?!
Can we go to Grandpa's house?
It's near here, isn't it?
But that's not Grandpa's house anymore.
Is somebody living there?
No. No one's living there now,
but the house is my uncle's...
My mom's older brother's house, so...
The family altar is there, too.
I see...
Fine. I'll ask my uncle if
we can just go in the yard.
Really?!
Only the yard!
Right!
I know the way!
I'm going to try and do
that assignment after all.
Seriously?!
Are you sure about this, Ma-chan?!
I'm alone for the sake of my work.
I have to do more work.
You're already working plenty!
You work enough for two people!
It's not enough yet...
I have to work so hard I forget
what I had for dinner last night.
Oh, come on. I always forget what I
had for dinner the previous night...
If I don't...
If I don't forget many things...
I...
We're almost there!
Kaga
It's the same as before, huh?
But you've totally changed...
They're gone!
The bellflowers!
The dirt is gone too!
The bellflowers were
precious to Grandpa!
I'm sure he didn't mean to remove them.
Uncle knows Grandpa's
favorite flower at least.
But they wither up when winter comes...
Maybe he didn't know that they
put out buds again in the spring.
The rocks, too...
If you don't spread them
all over like this,
weeds will spring up soon and
become tough to deal with.
Thankfully, we moved
Rin's fragrant olive.
That saved its life.
But thankfully we have Grandpa's
bellflowers at our house too, right?!
Because of that, they're still alive!
Exactly!
Maybe change isn't all bad.
But that grave will always
be Grandpa's grave, right?
Yeah!
Rin!
Happy birthday.
Happy Birthday, Rin-chan
It's a chocolate one!
Saionji-sensei, can you
do the final check?
Are you okay?
You really do seem to be in
over your head this time...
When you put it into words like that,
my hand stops working, so cut it out!
Go ahead.
I'll finish it, for sure.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Daikichi, the festival
stalls are gonna close!
No, they won't!
It sounds like Grandpa.
Kouki-kun is here!
What's wrong?
We're supposed to meet up
at the shrine, remember?
Mom is taking too long!
You're not wearing a yukata?
I can't jump with that!
Was that awesome or what?
Where's your mom?
She said she'll leave after her yukata
is on, so we should meet at the shrine.
Let's go!
Before the festival stalls close!
Daikichi, watch out for cars!
I know!
Wait! It's hard to run in geta!
I'll carry you!
Forget it!
You can carry me!